Guide to the University Planning Committee records, 1962-1973 UA.03.02.0014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
University Planning Committee records
1962-1973
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University University Planning Committee
UA.03.02.0014
4.5 Linear Feet
The collection consists of records relating to the academic, faculty, and institutional development of the University, as dealt with through this committee. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, agendas, proposals, and bound materials comprise this collection. Materials in this collection date from 1962 to 1973.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Transfer.
Historical Note
The University Planning Committee was constituted in October 1962. This committee served as the successor to the University Committee on Long-Range Planning. In October of 1964 the University Planning Committee combined with the University Policy Committee, forming the University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee (UPPAC). This new committee was responsible for University matters dealing with academic policy and physical planning. The UPPAC was in existence until 1969. In 1971, the University Planning Committee (UPC) was constituted by then-President Terry Sanford. The UPC was to assume the roles of the previous planning committees in that it was to "look at the past and make projections for the future in areas of enrollment, physical facilities, space, revenue sources of operating funds for the Medical Center, faculty retirement, campus plans, development, etc." The UPC was disbanded in 1973, and reappeared the next academic year as the University Planning Commission.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of records relating to the academic, faculty, and institutional development of the University, as dealt with through this committee. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, agendas, proposals, and bound materials comprise this collection. Materials in this collection date from 1962 to 1973.
Duke University. University Planning Committee; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Faculty
- University Planning Committee 1962-1964, 1
  - Agendas, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Commitment to Undergraduate Education - Report by Educational Goals Committee, 1964 October 10 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1962-1963 (Academic Year) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1963-1964 (Academic term) (Box 1)
  - Educational Goals Subcomittee, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    2 folders
  - Graduate Affairs Subcomittee, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Affairs Subcomittee, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Minutes 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Minutes 1963-1964 (Academic Term) (Box 1)
  - Reports, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- University Policy & Planning Advisory Committee 1964-1969, 2
  - Agendas, 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Maintaining Quality, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Committee to consider Regulations on Campus Drinking, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Year-Around Use of University Facilities, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Reports & Proposals, 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - Segregated Facilities, 1967 (Box 1)
- University Planning Committee 1971-1973, 3
  - Admissions & Financial Aid Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Agendas, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Athletics and Physical Education Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Development Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Development Subcommittee - Correspondence, 1972 April-May (Box 2)
  - Fine Arts Subcomittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Graduate Academic Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - International Programs Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Libraries Subcomittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Medial Center and Health Affairs, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Non-curricular life Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Physical Facilities, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Professional Schools Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Regional & State Affairs Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Final Report, Draft A, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Final Report, Draft B, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Final Report, Draft C, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Final Report, Draft D, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Report of Admissions & Financial Aid, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Report of Athletics & Physical Facilites Subcomittee, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Report of Faculty Development, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Report of Fine Arts Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Graduate Academic Programs, Vol. 1, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Graduate Academic Programs, Vol. 2, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Graduate Academic Programs, Vol. 3, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of International Programs, Vol. 1, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Report of International Programs, Vol. 2, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Report of Subcommittee on International Programs, Vol. 3, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Report of Subcommittee on Libraries, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Medical Center & Health Affairs Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Non-curricular life, Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Physical Facilites Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Professional Schools Subcommittee, Vol. 1, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Professional Schools Subcommittee, Vol. 2, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Report of Regional & State Subcommittee, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Report of Undergraduate Academic Programs, Vol. 1, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Report of Undergraduate Academic Programs, Vol. 2, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Undergraduate Academic Programs, 1971-1973 (Box 3)